[
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the EAPOL 4-way handshake?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Authenticated key agreement for session keys",
      "User authentication",
      "Negotiation of radio parameters",
      "Distribution of long term keys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How does WEP provide replay protection?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "By using a sequence counter",
      "By using an integrity check value",
      "By using a frame specific encryption key",
      "WEP does not provide replay protection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many messages are exchanged in a group key handshake?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the five input values to the CCMP Decryption block?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Key, Data, Nonce, PN, AAD",
      "Key, Data, Nonce, MAC1, MAC2",
      "Key, Data, Nonce, MIC, AAD",
      "Key, Data, Nonce1, Nonce2, IV"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a mutable field in CCMP?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "A header field that is not integrity protected because it can be modified in transit",
      "A header field that is integrity protected because it will not be modified in transit",
      "A header field indicating if the frame has been modified in transit",
      "A header field that specifies whether or not a frame can be modified in transit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the major weakness in WEP, exploited by the PTW attack used in the lab?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Weak IVs",
      "IV reuse",
      "Short encryption key",
      "Correlation between keystream and RC4 key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are EAP messages transported between the authenticator and the authentication server in RSN?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Encapsulated in EAPOL",
      "Encapsulated in RADIUS",
      "Encapsulated in 802.1X",
      "Encapsulated in TLS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which frame types are cryptographically protected by 802.11i?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Data frames only",
      "Data and Management frames",
      "Data and Control frames",
      "Data, Management and Control frames\n2\nTTM4137 Final Exam, Dec. 17, 2015"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which standard actually enabled practical DoS attacks on 802.11i TKIP?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "802.11e Quality of Service Enhancements",
      "802.11h Spectrum and Transmit Power Management Extensions",
      "802.11i MAC Security Enhancements",
      "802.11k Radio Resource Measurement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does Windows 10 Wi-Fi Sense allow sharing of 802.11i keys?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "No, Wi-Fi Sense only shares SSIDs",
      "No, Wi-Fi Sense only shares location information for open hotspots",
      "Yes, the PSK",
      "Yes, the PTK"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does Windows 10 Wi-Fi Sense enforce access control to wireless networks?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, by using 802.1X",
      "Yes, by using the Windows Filtering Platform on the client",
      "Yes, by transmitting an Access Control List to the AP",
      "No, Wi-Fi Sense does not enforce access control"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does GSM provide mutual authentication?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, but only between the SIM and the home network",
      "Yes, but only between the SIM and the visited network",
      "No, the SIM does not authenticate the network",
      "No, the network does not authenticate the SIM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is backward key separation achieved during handovers over X2 connections in EPS?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "X2 handovers in EPS do not support backward key separation",
      "The target eNB receives a fresh key from the MME",
      "The source eNB securely deletes the key after transmitting it to the target eNB",
      "The source eNB applies a one-way function to the key before transmitting it to the target eNB"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the EPS key derivation function constructed?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["AES-CBC", "AES-CCM", "HMAC-SHA256", "HMAC-MD5"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How long are the cipher key (CK) and integrity key (IK) used in UTRAN, and how are they obtained if a GSM SIM is used to access a UTRAN?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "CK 128 bits, IK 128 bits, obtained using a conversion function",
      "CK 256 bits, IK 256 bits, obtained using a conversion function",
      "CK 128 bits, IK 128 bits, distributed from the AuC to the SIM",
      "CK 256 bits, IK 256 bits, distributed from the AuC to the SIM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is cryptographic network separation (in EPS)?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "All network entities have separate cryptographic keys",
      "Communication between different core networks is protected by IPSec",
      "The cryptographic network is separated from the core network",
      "The derived keys are specific to the serving network"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which values are sent from the AuC to the VLR/SGSN during 3G/UMTS authentication?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "RAND, XRES, Kc, AUTN",
      "RAND, XRES, CK, IK, AUTN",
      "RAND, XRES, CK, IK, AK",
      "RAND, XRES, CK, IK, SQN\n3\nTTM4137 Final Exam, Dec. 17, 2015"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which UMTS entities implement the functions f1-f5, f1* and f5*?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["UE and VLR", "UE and AuC", "USIM and VLR", "USIM and AuC"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does EPS provide a more complex key hierarchy than UMTS and GSM?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "To support more cryptographic algorithms",
      "For backward compatibility with UMTS and GSM",
      "To support cryptographic key separation and enable more frequent key renewal",
      "To support other types of access networks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Will 3G USIMs work with EPS UE handsets?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, but only after a firmware update",
      "Yes, because the ME computes the EPS keys",
      "No, because USIMs do not support generation of EPS keys",
      "No, because EPS uses different AKA functions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does EPID have a mechanism for key revocation?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Yes, using a revocation list",
      "Yes, using the Online Certificate Status Protocol",
      "No, EPID does not need a mechanism for key revocation",
      "No, because the designers of EPID considered key compromise a low risk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the EPID join procedure?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "To prove membership of a group",
      "To join a network",
      "To join two network messages into one",
      "To assign a private key to a device"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which three entities participate in the WPS configuration process?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Supplicant, Authenticator, Authentication Server",
      "Enrollee, Access Point, Registrar",
      "Client, Access Point, Verifier",
      "Station, Authenticator, Registrar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many messages are exchanged in the WPS in-band registration protocol?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["2", "4", "6", "8"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol state will an 802.11 STA be in after having received a deauthentication notification message?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["State 1", "State 2", "State 3", "State 4"]
  }
]
